Sharon Scheel

7685 SW Whitford Drive, Portland, OR 97223 503-360-77982 ~ sharonscheel@gmail.com

March 25, 2013

Staffing Solutions 610 SW Broadway Suite 500 Portland, OR 97205

Dear Hiring Manager:

Your posting for an Administrative Assistant indicates requirements which closely match my background and expertise. I have enclosed my résumé to provide a summary of my qualifications and background for your review.

With over eight years of professional administrative experience at Florida State University and Willamette Valley Wineries Association I believe I have the skills and experience you are seeking. My responsibilities included completing purchase requisitions; extensive writing and proofreading; providing professional customer service to internal and external clients; and acting as the primary liaison for the association. I have advanced computer skills in Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, Access and various proprietary database programs. I am fully proficient in business English and have a thorough understanding corporate/business policies, procedures, and practices.

With excellent organizational and communications skills, an outstanding work ethic, and the ability to work well in both team-oriented and self-directed environments, I am prepared to exceed your expectations. I would welcome the opportunity to meet with you to discuss my qualifications and candidacy in further detail. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely, Sharon Scheel

Sharon Scheel

7685 SW Whitford Drive, Portland, OR 97223 503-360-7982 ~ sharonscheel@gmail.com

Education:

- Portland State University: Bachelors of Science, Geography, 2000, GPA 3.78
- Clackamas Community College: Associate Science Degree, General Science, 1996, GPA 3.9
- Certificates: Florida State University
 - Grant Writing
 - Excel Intermediate and Advanced
 - Photoshop Beginning
 - o Access Beginning, Intermediate, Advanced, and Expert
 - Business Writing Series (includes Writing Effectively and Persuasively, Recording Meeting Minutes, and Program Grant Writing)

Computer Skills:

- Operating systems: PC and Mac
- Software: Excel, Word, Access, Power Point, Publisher, Outlook

Selected Professional Experience:

• Administrative/Office Management:

Organized, managed, and coordinated administrative duties. Provided back-up and support for human resources, assisted with vacancy postings, reference checks, I-9 verifications, and handling confidential files. Created documents, spreadsheets, and presentations incorporating graphs, charts and graphics utilizing Word, Excel, Publisher, and PowerPoint. Acted as primary contact and liaison for internal and external clients. Responsible for extensive writing and proofreading, preparing mail merges for mass mailings, calendar management, purchasing office supplies and equipment, maintaining multiple databases and contact lists. Purchased office supplies, equipment and printed materials. Maintained inventory and ordered association products for events and website sales. Updated and maintained multiple databases including contact lists of vendors, clients and members.

• Research:

Conducted research, studies, audits, and assignments to assist faculty. Collected records and evaluated information for special studies, programs and projects; wrote correspondence, summary reports, narratives or reports related to work assignment.

• Customer Service:

Established and maintained excellent relationships with a broad range of constituents including deans, faculty, staff, vendors, board of directors, winery owners, event guests, business leaders, government officials, and the general public. As primary contact and liaison for both internal and external clients I managed email, phone, and voicemail communications.

Employment History:

<u>Five Rivers LLC</u> – Lafayette, LA

Photointerpreter 1

August 2011 to March 2012

Responsible for the interpretation of remotely sensed data, primarily aerial photography and digital imagery, using Arc GIS and digital stereoscopic equipment.

• Florida State University – Tallahassee, Fl

Administrative Assistant - Center for Teaching & Learning

November 2006 to June 2010

Coordinated all office management and administrative tasks including preparation of materials for events, and serving as the program's primary contact person. Conducted research, collected, and managed data for a variety of projects and reports. Planned and coordinated a two day, multivenue graduate teaching assistant training conference as well as a variety of receptions, seminars, and symposia. Developed promotional materials, press releases, and articles publicizing events and activities for publication in the university's magazine, newspaper, and websites; which resulted in a significant increase in attendance.

• National High Magnetic Field Lab - Tallahassee, FL

Budget and Grant Assistant

June 2006 to November 2006 (Temporary Position)

Created an Access database for tracking individual employee's project information, which resulted in improved monthly reporting capabilities. Edited and proofread National Science Foundation Grant proposals and assisted Controller in preparing an \$11.9 million operating budget grant and a \$4 million project grant.

• Randstad Work Solutions, Remedy Intelligent Staffing, Adecco

Jacksonville & Tallahassee, FL

November 2005 to May 2006

Various temporary positions including budget reconciliation, office management, general office, and administrative duties.

Willamette Valley Wineries Association – Portland, OR

Administrative Assistant

January 2000 to September 2005

Organized, managed, and coordinated office tasks including administrative duties and served as the primary contact person for both organizations. Managed and maintained multiple databases. Planned a variety of meetings and events for association members. Assisted with planning for Oregon Pinot Camp, an annual three day, multi-venue educational conference for 300 top wine trade guests from across the country. Coordinated membership services including researching and identifying potential new members, prepared and sent new member packets, and processed applications. Developed and coordinated production of promotional materials, including extensive editing and proofreading. Created job postings, screened resumes, conducted interviews, verified references, and trained seasonal staff.

<u>Columbia Medial Group</u> – Portland, OR

Administrative Assistant

August 1992 to September 1994

Supported senior management and medical clinic directors by organizing business operations and activities. Conducted research, gathering and interpreting significant amounts of data utilizing information for internal reports as well as reports sent to clinics, hospitals, and sponsoring HMO. Successfully managed a variety of simultaneous projects involving corporate office departments and clinics. Provided back-up and support for human resources, assisted with vacancy postings, reference checks, I-9 verifications, and handling confidential files.